<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="en">
	<title>Cicero Is Back</title>
	<subtitle>I am writing about my experiences as a naval navel-gazer.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://ciceroisback.com/blog/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://ciceroisback.com/blog/"/>
	<updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://ciceroisback.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Cicero</name>
		<email>dev@ciceroisback.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>StephenHall</title>
		<link href="https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/StephenHall/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/StephenHall/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On [[Mar 18th, 2023]], Stephen and I had an interesting conversation about swagger. He likes it; I don&#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for Stephen to come to Gutenberg
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#AndrewDewberry said that all my brothers have a similar tone of voice to me; Stephen will have to change his voicde&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#BirthdayCards
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Stephen,
Happy Birthday! Congratulations on turning 18 :) I hope this year brings you a lot of opportunities to grow and mature as a man and as a Christian. You&#39;ve come a long ways in the last couple of years, and I anticipate even more good things to come&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this postcard on my senior trip to California. Walking among the massive redwood trees, I understood a bit why you like spending so much  time in nature. They were just so majestic and peaceful and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pilgrimfeet - Spotify name &amp;amp; MC name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Leadership Voice Class</title>
		<link href="https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro-to-the-class&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Intro to the Class &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;led by #DavidSnider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;giantworldwide.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary conflict: Everyone speaks. Not everyone is heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team leaders rarely, if ever, hear the truth from their people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a result, team members feel misunderstood and undervalued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, leaders lose their influence as leaders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assumptions-in-this-class&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Assumptions in this class &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our Voice is made up of all 5 Voices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some Voices are more natural to us than others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;maturity allows us to value the contribution each Voice brings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is not a personality profile to put you in a box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nature, nurture, and choice have all played a part in your Voices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;don&#39;t assume you know what someone else&#39;s Foundational Voice is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;don&#39;t assume you know what each word means&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;voice-rating-system&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Voice Rating System &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;:green: - my Foundational Voice, my default pattern of communication and thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;:yellow: - not my foundational voice, but I value it and it&#39;s easily accessible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;:red: - not my found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-5-voices&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The 5 Voices &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nurturer-yellow&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Nurturer ==:yellow:== &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
champion of people, relational values, and harmony
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they intuitively feel how an organization will react to a new idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they defend values - people will always come before profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they function as the relational oil inside teams and organizations
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can restate assertions to keep people from talking past each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are pragmatic realists who ask &amp;quot;has this really been thought through?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they take genuine delight in celebrating the achievements of others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are natural team players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they can become overly resistant to change &amp;amp; demonstrate passive aggressive tendencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they rarely value the contribution they make; susceptible to imposter syndrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion of:&lt;/strong&gt; people, relational harmony, values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch out for:&lt;/strong&gt; nurturers have a fear of conflict and often won&#39;t speak out, beware of silence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to empower them:&lt;/strong&gt; let them speak first, affirm their competence and the genuine value of their contribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population:&lt;/strong&gt; 43%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 1/7, very quiet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creative-red&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Creative ==:red:== &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
future ideas, innovation and organizational integrity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are the conceptual architects and love to think outside the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they function as an &amp;quot;early warning system&amp;quot; for teams, often seeing the opportunities and dangers before everyone else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are never satisfied with the status quo - they inherently believe things can always be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the vision is compelling the word &amp;quot;can&#39;t&amp;quot; is not in their vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they often struggle with the fact that &amp;quot;people never seem to fully understand my ideas&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they exhibit a strong social conscience and desire for personal and organizational integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being internal perfectionists, they can often fail to celebrate the 90% that has been achieved, focusing instead on the 10% that hasn&#39;t!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion of:&lt;/strong&gt; future ideas, innovation, and organizational integrity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch out for:&lt;/strong&gt; creatives can struggle to communicate effectively and have idealist perfectionist tendencies (aiming for utopia); this leads to them being hard on themselves when they&#39;re not perfect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to empower them:&lt;/strong&gt; don&#39;t judge them on what they say first, help them communicate their ideas. let them know it&#39;s ok to be wrong sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population:&lt;/strong&gt; 9%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 2/7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;guardian-green&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Guardian ==:green:== &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
due diligence, resources, and effective
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have a relentless commitment to asking the difficult questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they will always seek to honor the past as teams look towards the future - &lt;em&gt;this is the only one I don&#39;t identify with&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they accept as personal the commitment to deliver projects on time and on budget
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(makes a good project manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have the ability to detach decision-making from personal sentiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are naturally risk-averse asking &amp;quot;is it worth the risk and investment&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they respect and value logic, order, systems and repeatable processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their desire for truth and right decisions can sometimes override the feelings of others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion of:&lt;/strong&gt; Due diligence, resources, and efficient systems and processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch out for:&lt;/strong&gt; guardians are risk averse, can be negative and bring excessive critique
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m too soft-spoken for excessive critique, and I&#39;m not very negative, so I don&#39;t identify with this much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to empower them:&lt;/strong&gt; welcome their challenging critique and commitment to due diligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population:&lt;/strong&gt; 30%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3/7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;connector-green-yellow&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Connector ==:green-yellow:== &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
champion of relational networks, internal collaboration, and effective communication
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are persuasive and inspirational communicators - rallying people to causes and things they believe in - &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are incredibly resourceful - &amp;quot;Whatever we need, I can get it or I have a source&amp;quot; - &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they have the capacity to maintain a large number of relationships - &lt;em&gt;not so much&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when they see people again after a long time, they can instantly reconnect with them. - &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they know how to connect with people and their aspirations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they need appreciation and credit for making key connections - &amp;quot;Are you aware of what I&#39;ve done?&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their people-pleasing tendencies mean they often struggle to bring effective challenge; they hesitate to push others - &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they often struggle to hear or engage fully with critical feedback - &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&#39;s very little separation between their work and personal lives, so they take critical feedback personally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion of:&lt;/strong&gt; relational networks, internal collaboration, and effective communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch out for:&lt;/strong&gt; connectors always interpret challenge of their ideas as personal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to empower them:&lt;/strong&gt; give them time to share their ideas and passions, appreciate before you critique
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their ideas are like art, and they need time to deliver the ethos of the idea, not just the mechanics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population:&lt;/strong&gt; 11%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 5/7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pioneer-red&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Pioneer ==:red:== &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
champion of strategic vision, results-focused, and problem-solving
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they approach life with an &amp;quot;anything is possible!&amp;quot; attitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visioning and shaping a scalable future is always the highest priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their strategic military thinking makes them incredibly effective at aligning people, systems and resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;winning is a massive driver, they hate to give up and will drive their team long after others would have given up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are powerful communicators, using logic and rationality to provide an attractive and compelling vision of the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the immature Pioneer can often appear very arrogant with a &amp;quot;me focused&amp;quot; agenda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they quickly dismiss the contributions of those they don&#39;t believe to be competent or experienced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can struggle with ego&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champion of:&lt;/strong&gt; strategic vision, results-focused, and problem-solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch out for:&lt;/strong&gt; pioneers lack sensitivity, can be unwilling to listen, and perceived as arrogant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to empower them:&lt;/strong&gt; don&#39;t worry - they empower themselves. just affirm their competence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population:&lt;/strong&gt; 7%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 8/7, loud to the point of distortion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-voice-order&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;My Voice Order &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guardian - green&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connector - green/yellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nurturer - yellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative - red&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pioneer - red&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assignments&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Assignments &lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://ciceroisback.com/blog/blog/Leadership%20Voice%20Class/&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 2nd session
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you speak, complete your sentences and stay focused on one idea at a time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I&#39;m speaking, I often lose my train of thought or just trail off into nothingness. I often lose a word that I want to say, and then have to stop what I&#39;m saying to think of it. I just don&#39;t feel like I can communicate ideas coherently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of the problem arises because I&#39;m a verbal processor, so I don&#39;t think about things unless I&#39;m talking about them. However, I don&#39;t talk about things with people very often. This leads to me not developing thoughts on things very often. Generally I sit down to have a conversation with someone, and I don&#39;t have any thoughts to provide on the topic. So, I end up just sitting and letting them talk, and not having anything to say back. It&#39;s only after I&#39;ve gone away from the conversation that I can come up with a response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And having said all that, I&#39;m not completely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When people reject your idea it&#39;s not as personal as it sometimes feels.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the same vein, pretty often I&#39;m reticent to share my ideas, because I&#39;m afraid that people won&#39;t like them. I haven&#39;t had enough time to develop my thoughts, because I haven&#39;t been talking to people. This is just a vicious cycle where I don&#39;t do any thinking, and I don&#39;t do any talking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And when I do share my ideas, and people dislike them, I tend to take it hard, especially if they are ideas that I&#39;ve spent a lot of time thinking about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess the upshot of all this is that I don&#39;t feel currently able to share my thoughts and ideas effectively. My goal for improving this is to do a lot more talking to myself. this will include techniques like talking quietly under my breath without moving my lips to slow down and focus my thought processes. I&#39;ll talk to myself about various topics that I want to develop thoughts on, then seek out a person to talk to about that topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
